我已经设置好了，这是因为镜头太简单了。
I've set us up already, and this is because lenses are so simple.
它们太复杂了，就像一个非常深刻的主题，
They're so complex, it's like a really deep subject,
你可以用镜头做任何事情。
you can do anything and everything with lenses.
您可以使用内置镜头的函子做任何事情
You can do everything you can with functors with lenses which are built
在函子上，我们将使用镜头的方式非常简单，
on functors, and the way we're gonna just use lenses is pretty light,
但要知道你可以做最了不起的事情，
but know that you can do the most amazing things,
您可以仅用镜头重写每个应用程序。
you can rewrite every app in just lenses.
[笑] 虽然，我认为很多人都反对，因为 Haskell 和
[LAUGH] Although, I think that a lot of people have push back because Haskell and
其他镜头库根据所有这些小波浪运算符定义它，并且
other lens libraries defined it in terms of all these little squiggly operators and
就像这是什么？
it's just like what is this?
它读不正确，所以这是这些语言中镜头的一个缺点。
It doesn't read right, so that's one drawback of lenses in those languages.
这里我们只有函数，它们很好，但是你可以定义一个镜头
Here we just have functions and they're fine, but you can define a lens
映射到事物上，你可以定义一个镜头，所以退后一步。
that maps over things, you can define a lens, so take a step back.
所以我在这里所做的是我从 Lambda 中引入了镜头库，
So what I've done here is I brought in the lens library from Lambda,
这是一个相当天真。
it's a fairly naive.
如果你打算使用镜头库并且喜欢真正致力于镜头，
If you're gonna use a lens library and like really commit to lenses,
我强烈建议环顾四周，我认为有一种叫做optica，
I would highly recommend looking around there's one called optica I think,
然后还有一些其他的。
and then there's a few other ones out there.
但绝对想专注于[笑]没有双关语，
But definitely wanna focus on [LAUGH] no pun intended,
这个课程的顶级部分，顶级，简单的东西。
the top parts, the top level, simple stuff for this class.
所以我通常定义一个小的命名空间对象，
So I usually define a little namespaced object,
因为我的镜头往往与应用程序中的东西同名。
because my lenses tend to be the same names as the things in the app.
所以我喜欢用 L 来命名它，[笑] 而我们所做的就是我们已经说过
So I like to namespace it with L, [LAUGH] and what we've done is we've said
LensProp(&#39;name&#39;)，这就是名称lens，我们有lensProp Street。
LensProp('name'), and that'll be the name lens, and we have lensProp Street.
那是街道镜头lensProp地址，那是地址镜头，
And that's the street lens lensProp address, that's the address lens,
我将如何使用它？
how would I use that?
好吧，我们有视图，可以查看这些东西之一，
Well, we have view and over to view one of these things,
我有这个嵌套对象，如果我想查看街道，请说，
I have this nested object and if I wanna view the street say,
我只会调用视图，我会将它传递给我想要的镜头。
I'll just call view, I'll pass it the lens that I want.
Street 和 street 需要一个地址，对吗？
Street, and street takes an address, right?
所以我必须真正撰写[(L.address, L.street,
So I have to actually compose[(L.address, L.street,
)] 镜头组合成函数，它们让我跳进地址和
)] lenses composed like functions, and they let me jump into the address and
到街上，我可以在这个用户上看到它。
into the street and I can just view that on this user.
所以让我们做的是console.res，
So let's do that was console.res,
console.log(res) 和
console.log(res) and
让我们的节点镜头 0 被命名为枫树。
let's node lenses 0 there is is named maple.
让我们取名字 L.name，是枫树。
Let's get the name L.name, Is maple.
所以我能够跳入陡峭的嵌套结构
So I was able to jump in to the steeply nested structure
通过属性的组合，这很酷。
through composition of properties, that's cool.
如果做完了，过度允许我修改toUpper，
What if do over, over allows me to modify that toUpper,
所以我可以说嘿，跳进名字，名字部分和
so I can say hey, jump into the name, name part and
让我们把它拉到我丢失的街道 addrStreetName [笑] 中。
let's just pull this out into a street addrStreetName [LAUGH] that I lost it.
很好，是我复制的吗？
That's fine, did I copy it?
我复制了它，好吧 addrStreetName，然后
I copied it sweet all right addrStreetName, and
我们只想说这个镜头，我们要把它调高。
we're just gonna say over this lens, we're gonna turn it to upper.
对我来说有趣的是，这提供了一个非常，
And what's interesting to me is that this provides a very,
非常干净的方式一直跳到那里，改变它并
very clean way to jump all the way down there, change it and
把整个事情找回来，它是不可变的。
get the whole thing back and it's immutable.
它沿途复制了它，并且可以以非常有效的方式进行。
It made a copy of it along the way, and it can do so in a very efficient way.
如果我们正在考虑函子，我们正在考虑这些属性
And if we're thinking about functors, and we're thinking about these properties as
有点像打开一个盒子然后拿到下一件事
kind of like opening up a box and getting the next thing,
打开那个盒子，拿到下一件事，然后把它们全部装回去。
and opening up that box and getting the next thing, then boxing them all back up.
地图就是这样工作的，对吧？
That's how maps work, right?
你正在对这些事情进行映射并脱离目标
You're mapping over these things and getting out of target and
然后把更多的东西放在一起。
then putting more back together.
这主要是这些在幕后实施的方式，
And that's largely how these are implemented under the hood,
也意味着我们可以开始制作了，我不认为这有L.mapped，
also means that we can start to make, I don't think this has L.mapped,
但如果我有一个Either.of这个名字，我完全可以做到。
but if I had a Either.of this name I could totally do that.
我完全可以说，跳进去检查我的任何一个，然后
I could totally say, jump in and go over my either, and
然后到名字，把它变成大写。
then get to the name, turn it to uppercase.
所以这可能在一个任务中，我们可以跳到函子里面
So this could be inside a task, and we can jump inside of functors
巨大结构不同部分的内部属性，
inside of properties inside of different parts of a giant structure,
击中那一块，然后将其全部放回原处。
hit that one piece and then put it all back together.
那是地图的定义，打开东西，让我们把它拿出来改变它
And that's map by definition, open stuff up, let's get it out and change it and
然后为你把它放回原处。
then puts it back together for you.
所以这东西变得非常非常强大，
So this stuff gets really, really powerful,
我们不会在这里这样做，但我确实有一个可以做到这一点的镜头包，
we're not gonna do that right here, but I do have a lens package that does do that,
如果你想看看我的 GitHub。
if you wanna look at my GitHub.
它只是移植了 Edward 提交的镜头库和
It was just porting Edward commits lens library and
现在大多数人都在使用专业仿函数镜头，是的。
most people these days are using pro functor lenses, yes.
&gt;&gt; 这些是否明确使用了观察者模式之类的东西，
&gt;&gt; Are these explicitly using something like an observer pattern,
或者这更像是阅读器模式文档？
or is this more like a reader mode documentation?
&gt;&gt; 这是一个很好的问题，所以我们不持有
&gt;&gt; That's a great question, so we're not holding
到 ref 并进行任何类型的有线更改。
on to a ref and having any kind of wired changes.
这非常类似于闭包引用的东西，或者
This is very similar to closures ref stuff, or
他们的视图库现在有点过时了，但是
they had that view library that's a little out of date now, but
它类似于这种东西，他们有点像对待镜片一样对待它。
it was similar to this stuff where they kinda treated it like lenses.
这是不同的，它实际上就像将属性视为函子一样
This is different, it's literally like treating properties as a functor and
有一个抽他们起来，改变东西，然后把它们放回去，和
there's a Pumping them up and changing stuff and putting them back, and
profunctor，镜头的实现有点不同，给你相同的
profunctor, lenses are implemented a little bit different give you the same
力量，可能是更大的力量。
power, probably more power.
你可以跳过函子和属性中的各种东西，
And you could jump through functors and all sorts of stuff in properties,
你也可以用一个镜头来做到这一点，嘿，你知道吗？
you could also do this with like a lens that says, hey, you know what?
我要抢第一个或第零个，对吗？
I'm gonna grab the first or the zeroth right?
应该是镜头道具，哎呀，0，
Should be Lens prop, whoops, 0,
那么我们可以说，是的，我们有用户，
then we could say, yeah, we have users,
对，我们将从 L.0 开始。
right, and we'll just start with L.0.
我们可以传入用户，
And we could pass in users,
现在我们正在跳过所有的数组，
now we're jumping through the array, of all the,
我想现在必须把第一个拿出来看看。
I guess have to grab the first one out now to look at it.
但是看，我们跳过了用户数组抢到了第一个，然后
But look, we jumped through the array of users grab the first one, and
然后换枫。
then change maple.
再一次，如果我要在支持该功能的不同镜头库上调用映射
And again if I was to call mapped on a different lens library that supported that
它会贯穿每个人，改变每个名字，并在可变的情况下做这一切。
it would run through everyone and change every name and do it all on mutable.
所以这些真的，真的很强大，他们真的只是吸气剂和
So these are really, really powerful, they're really just getters and
setter 是不可变的，让你可以像函数一样组合。
setters that are unmutable and let you compose like functions.
你有点像我现在有这个街道名称的参考，正如你提到的。
You're kinda like I have this ref to the street name now, as you kinda mentioned.
这几乎就像一个大结构中的一个大点的参考，你可以
It's almost like a reference to a big spot in a big structure and you're able to just
进入并更改它，然后在不丢失数据的情况下返回。
get in there and change it, and come back out without loosing your data.
这真的很好，特别是如果你正在做这个非常好的作品，并且
Which is really nice, especially if you're doing this really nice composition, and
你就像在你的作品中间，
you're just like in the middle of your composition,
你想改变一点点价值。
you wanna change one little value.
但通常使用 setter，你会扔掉整个结构，改变
But typically with a setter, you would throw away the entire structure, change
价值，然后随着你的作品的进行，你已经失去了整个结构。
the value and then as your composition goes, you've lost the entire structure.
镜头保留了结构，所以当你运行你的功能管道时，
Lenses preserve the structure, so as you run through your pipeline of functions,
结构保持不变，您只是更改了一件。
the structure is maintained, you just changed one piece.
&gt;&gt;此人说值得一提的镜头构图倒退，但
&gt;&gt; This person said worth mentioning lenses composed backwards, but
你之前已经介绍过了 &gt;&gt; 值得一提的是，肯定的，
you already covered that earlier &gt;&gt; That is worth mentioning yes for sure,
通常组合会运行名称，街道，地址，bomp。
normally composition would run name, street, address, bomp.
它会从右到左，
It would go right to left,
这实际上从左到右是的，这是很好的提及，很好的呼吁。
this actually goes left to right yeah that's good mention, good call out.
如果您开始了解它是如何实现的，则镜头向后组合
Lenses composed backwards for if you start to see how it's implemented you
明白为什么，但奇怪的是看到有像从左到右的组合而不是
see why but it's weird to see that there are composed like left to right instead of
从右到左，你总是看到。
right to left where you always see.
但这是一个标准的函数组合，
But this is a standard function composition,
这不是一个特殊的镜头组合。
this is not a special lens composition.